<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20051107-newsletter.xml" lang="pl">
<title>Tygodnik Gentoo</title>
<subtitle>7 listopada 2005</subtitle>
<author title="Redaktor naczelny">
<mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="deadhead@gechi.it">Andrea Perotti</mail>
</author>
<abstract>Wydanie Tygodnika Gentoo z 7 listopada 2005.</abstract>
<summary/>
<version>Wolumin 4, numer 44</version>
<date>2005-11-07</date>

<!-- Gentoo News -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo news</title>
<section>
<title>New GLEP to manage important update information</title>
<body>
<p>
One of the longest-standing discussions between Gentoo developers and users
centers around the little <path>einfo</path> warnings that are being
displayed briefly whenever you emerge a package that contains crucial
additional information on how to upgrade things, and what configuration
files to watch out for. They're important, very much so, but in essence
useful only to those who watch a compilation scroll past their screens,
and despite several earlier efforts have never been made to stick around
other places in Portage to be consulted later, at leisure, after a lengthy
update of several packages at once. Now <mail link="ciaranm@gentoo.org">Ciaran
McCreesh</mail> has set out for yet another attempt at solving this problem:
He is the author of <uri link="/proj/en/glep/glep-0042.html">a formal
proposal</uri> for an automatic distribution system for critical news that
is to complement existing Gentoo information channels (Forums,
<path>gentoo-announce</path> mailing list, website and the GWN), but aims
to be part of Portage itself in order to get pushed out to Gentoo users
without them having to pull anything in.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Future zone -->
<!-- User Stories -->
<chapter>
<title>User stories</title>
<section>
<title>Interview with Jacob Lindberg, a Linux Specialist for
Brenntag Nordic</title>
<body>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20051107_jacob.jpg" short="Jacob Lindberg"
caption="Jacob Lindberg, Linux Specialist for Brenntag Nordic" />

<p><e>Who are you and where do you work?</e></p>

<p>I'm Jacob Lindberg, 30 years old working as a Linux Specialist for
Brenntag Nordic in Denmark since March 2004. I recently got married,
have no kids, but a dog and 2 blue-russian cats, Phoebe and Joey, named
after Friends (the comedy).</p>

<p>Brenntag Nordic has offices and plants in Denmark, Sweden, Norway and Finland
and is a part of the Brenntag Group. They <uri
link="http://www-306.ibm.com/software/success/cssdb.nsf/CS/DNSD-5QJENP">consolidated
a lot of their servers</uri> to Linux in 2003. Unfortunately the cost
of external consultants was very high, services went down from time to
time, and the consultants didn't have the knowledge to fix the various
problems. The solutions were based on SuSE. As an old FreeBSD man, I
don't like anything in binaries. I want my stuff from source and
configurable. And as a lot of other Linux guys I have been through the
hell of RPM dependencies. No more! This is why way back Gentoo caught
my attention, and it has never left it since.
</p>
<p><e>Where do you use Gentoo? What did it replace?</e></p>

<p>We have no Linux servers not running Gentoo, so it's everywhere
that's possible. We got the following services from Gentoo:</p>

<ul>
<li>Samba, doing PDC, fileserver and Image server</li>
<li>Squid, doing proxy and filtering</li>
<li>Postfix and spamassassin, scanning all incoming and outgoing emails</li>
<li>Bind9, running our dns internally and externally</li>
<li>IPtables, running as firewall between our datacenter and our 10 locations (clients)</li>
<li>rsync, doing our Gentoo mirror</li>
<li>proftpd and tftp, doing images for Cisco equipment and such</li>
<li>Backup server</li>
<li>Log server</li>
</ul>

<p><e>Why do you use POWER4/5 machines? </e></p>

<p>Our iSeries machines are running SAP and Lotus Notes in the OS400
environment. The rest are Linux LPARs (logical partitions). In the new
year we will exchange the 870 with an 570 (i5), so everything is changed
to POWER5. The future plan is after changing to POWER5 we have a lot
more power and are able to supply more services. The reason for using
IBM hardware is that it's rock stable – and we have the opportunity to
run things directly from the OS400 also.</p>

<p>It's not easy to get something running on fairly non-documented
architecture (iSeries on PPC64) which was the situation back in early
2004. I started out with a pSeries LiveCD which didn't work at all.
After some tricks, and some help from the community I managed to get a
nws working which contained the LiveCD, and a kernel in the IFS. Now I
could boot Gentoo. This was done on my old 270 (RS/6000 processor as far
as I remember). This was quickly adapted to the 825 (POWER4) and 870
(POWER4). Today the 2005.0 and 2005.1 LiveCD are working on the i5
machines, but still not on the 825 and 870 machine.</p>

<p>The difference between x86 and PPC64 is mostly when installing
and configuring, especially the kernel. All your environment has to be
configured correctly for the PPC64 to work also. When working inside
Gentoo you don't see any big difference except <c>uname</c> returns another
architecture. This is because of the way Gentoo works.</p>

<p><e>Where does Gentoo need improvement?</e></p>

<p>I'm applying to become a member of the PPC64 developer team. In this
way, I can be a part of the improvement. I think the <uri
link="http://glep.gentoo.org">GLEP webpage</uri> shows some nice features
for the future.</p>

<p><e>What are your experiences with the Gentoo community?</e></p>

<p>It's amazing how many people are contributing to the community. This is
why I want to do it also. But my experience is that it's hard to find a
problem which can't be solved with the help from the community. So it's
very positive.</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo Stories -->
<!-- Developer of the week -->
<!-- Heard in the community: gentoo-dev, gentoo-user, forums -->
<chapter>
<title>Społeczność Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Lista dyskusyjna gentoo-dev</title>
<body>
<p><b>Getting important updates to users</b></p>
<p>
Jedne z największych wątków z ostatniego tygodnia rozdzielił się na cztery
osobne gorące dyskusje dotyczące jednego z głównych, do tej pory nie
rozwiązanego, problemu Gentoo Linux:<br/> Jak upewnić się że użytkownicy zostaną
poinformowani o aktualizacjach i innych ważnych informacjach związanych z nowymi
wersjami pakietów.?<br/> Mamy stronę gentoo.org, kanały RSS, Tygodnik Gentoo,
informacje zawartą w pakietach itd. - ale nie ma żadnego centralnego systemu
informowania o aktualizacjach. Propozycje GLEP autorstwa <mail
link="chriswhite@gentoo.org">Chrisa White'a</mail> i <mail
link="ciaranm@gentoo.org">Ciarana McCreesha</mail> szybko zamieniły się w
niezwykle ostrą dyskusję dotyczącą XML-a i innych rzeczy.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/32380">Getting important updates to users</uri></li>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/32427">GLEP 42 (Was: Getting Important Updates To Users) </uri></li>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/32438">GLEP ??: Critical News Reporting </uri></li>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/32657">GLEP 42 "Critical News Reporting" Round Two </uri></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Propozycja zmian w profilu bazowym Gentoo/ALT</b></p>
<p>
<mail link="flameeyes@gentoo.org">Diego Pettenò</mail> przedstawił poprawki dla
profilu bazowego, tak by był on bardziej ogólny i nie zawierał specyficznych dla
linuksa parametrów, wszystkie one zostały przeniesione do "default-linux".
Dzięki tej zmianie stworzenie Gentoo/BSD jest coraz bliżej.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/32507">Proposed
changes to base profile for Gentoo/ALT </uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo international -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo international</title>
<section>
<title>Italy: GeCHI conference in November</title>
<body>
<p>
26 November 2005 is going to be the date for the 5th time that Italy's
open-source movement organizes a national Linux Day, and the 3rd time that this
Italy-wide event is a chance for the ever-growing Italian Gentoo users
community to prepare for some evangelism of their own. This year the 3rd
national meeting called Gentoo Day will be organized in collaboration with the
<uri link="http://www.velug.it">VELug</uri> (Venice Free Software Users Group).
Thanks to the support of the local authorities, the location of this year's
meeting will be Villa Franchin, Viale Garibaldi 155 (quartiere
Carpenedo-Bissuola), in the city of Mestre, near Venice.
</p>
<p>
Gentooists active in the <uri link="http://www.gechi.it">Gentoo Channel Italia</uri>
(GeCHI) framework will present some talks about different topics starting from
an "Introduction to Gentoo", to "Gentoo Linux Installer" to "Having fun with
Gentoo" ending with "Gimp: From 0 to Dalì". There will be the possibility to
buy some new cool gadgets, like the world-famous GeCHI T-Shirt or some stickers
and posters.
</p>
<p>
Don't miss this chance to meet and mingle with other Italian Gentoo users and
developers! If you want to join the GeCHI in this endeavour check <uri
link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic-p-2853724.html">this Forum
thread</uri> and the <uri
link="http://www.gechi.it/forums/viewtopic.php?p=1632">GeCHI's own
forum</uri> (both links in Italian)."
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Japan: GentooJP receives Andrea Barisani</title>
<body>
<p>
The <uri link="http://www.gentoo.gr.jp">GentooJP crowd</uri> will play cicerone
to visiting Gentoo developer <mail link="lcars@gentoo.org">Andrea Barisani</mail>
with a nite-seeing tour of the more indigenous back alleys of Tokyo's Shibuya
district, on the schedule for Sunday, 13 November 2005. Andrea is in town for a
<uri link="/news/en/gwn/20051003-newsletter.xml#doc_chap2_sect2">presentation at
the PacSec conference</uri>, and if you would like to join the outing, make sure
you're at the Hachiko statue in front of Shibuya station by 18:30 hours.
</p>
<note>
Confirm your participation by sending a short note to the
<path>gentoojp-misc@ml.gentoo.gr.jp</path> mailing list, please.
</note>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Gentoo in the press -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo in the press</title>
<section>
<title>Desktop Linux (4 November 2005)</title>
<body>
<p>
A new book from O'Reilly, the <uri
link="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS6574473318.html">Linux Desktop
Pocket Reference</uri>, provides a concise overview of the "five most popular
distributions" listed in alphabetical order, Gentoo after Fedora, and
followed by Mandriva, SUSE and Ubuntu. Author David Brickner tries to cut
through the undergrowth of too much information that he finds "hard to sift
through it all, to know what is accurate and what is up-to-date," and which he
identifies as the "biggest obstacle to faster adoption of Linux on the desktop."
Chapter 1 containing a comparison of the five distributions is available as a
<uri link="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/linuxdesktoppr/chapter/ch01.pdf">PDF
sample document</uri>, and provides a particularly enthusiastic assessment of
Gentoo's main assets: Portage and the documentation.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Tips and Tricks -->
<!-- Gentoo developer moves -->
<chapter>
<title>Zmiana statusu deweloperów Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Odeszli</title>
<body>
<p>
Następujący deweloperzy opuścili projekt Gentoo w minionym tygodniu:
</p>
<ul>
<li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Przybyli</title>
<body>
<p>
Następujący deweloperzy przyłączyli się do projektu Gentoo w minionym tygodniu:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Markus Dittrich (markusle) - app-sci</li>
<li>Michael Cummings (mcummings - powrót po dwóch miesiącach) - perl</li>
<li>Alexey Chumakov (achumakov) - rosyjskie tłumaczenie</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Changes</title>
<body>
<p>
Następujący deweloperzy zmienili funkcję w projekcie Gentoo w minionym tygodniu:
</p>
<ul>
<li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo security -->
<chapter>
<title>Bezpieczeństwo Gentoo</title>
<!-- paste from the script -->
<section>
<title>libgda: Usterka format string</title>
<body>
<p>
Dwie usterki format string w libgda mogą doprowadzić do wykonania niepożądanego
kodu.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-01.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>QDBM, ImageMagick, GDAL: Usterki RUNPATH</title>
<body>
<p>
Wiele pakietów zawiera usterki RUNPATH, które mogą umożliwić, użytkownikom
należącym do grupy "portage", przekroczenie uprawnień.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-02.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>giflib: Wiele usterek</title>
<body>
<p>
giflib zawiera usterki w przetwarzaniu obrazów, które mogą doprowadzić do
wykonania niepożądanego kodu lub ataku Denial of Service.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-03.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>ClamAV: Wiele usterek</title>
<body>
<p>
ClamAV zawiera wiele usterek, które mogą doprowadzić do wykonania niepożądanego
kodu lub ataku Denial of Service.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-04.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>GNUMP3d: Usterki directory traversal oraz XSS</title>
<body>
<p>
GNUMP3d zawiera usterki umożliwiające przeprowadzenie ataków directory traversal
oraz cross-site scripting mogących doprowadzić do ujawnienia informacji.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-05.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>fetchmail: Ujawnienie hasła w fetchmailconf</title>
<body>
<p>
fetchmailconf nadaje niepoprawne prawa do plików, czasowo ujawniając prywatne
dane lokalnym użytkownikom.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-06.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>OpenVPN: Wiele usterek</title>
<body>
<p>
Klient OpenVPN zawiera usterki mogące doprowadzić do wykonania niepożądanego
kodu, a serwer OpenVPN jest podatny na ataki Denial of Service.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200511-07.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<!-- end of paste from the script -->
</chapter>

<!-- Bugzilla -->
<!-- paste from the script -->
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Statystyki</title>
<body>
<p>
Społeczność Gentoo używa Bugzilli (<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) do zgłaszania i śledzenia
błędów, ogłoszeń, sugestii oraz innych form kontaktu z deweloperami. Pomiędzy 29
października 2005, a 05 listopada 2005 aktywność w serwisie przedstawiała się
następująco:
</p>
<ul>
<li>zgłoszono 756 nowych bugów</li>
<li>zamknięto lub rozwiązano 437 bugów</li>
<li>36 uprzednio zamkniętych bugów zostało ponownie otwartych</li>
</ul>
<p>
Spośród 8861 obecnie otwartych bugów: 99 oznaczono jako 'blocker', 191 jako
'critical', a 552 jako 'major'.
</p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Zamknięte Bugi</title>
<body>
<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, które zamknęły najwięcej bugów w minionym
tygodniu, to:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="ppc-macos@gentoo.org">gentoo for mac os x</mail>, with 52
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=resolved&amp;bug_status=closed&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=fixed&amp;assigned_to=ppc-macos@gentoo.org">zamknięte bugi</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org">gentoo sound team</mail>, with 18
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=resolved&amp;bug_status=closed&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=fixed&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="graphics@gentoo.org">media-gfx herd</mail>, with 14
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=resolved&amp;bug_status=closed&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=fixed&amp;assigned_to=graphics@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="x86@gentoo.org">gentoo developers for the x86 architecture</mail>, with 12
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=resolved&amp;bug_status=closed&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=fixed&amp;assigned_to=x86@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org">Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, with 12
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="games@gentoo.org">Gentoo Games</mail>, with 12
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="security@gentoo.org">Gentoo Security</mail>, with 11
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="python@gentoo.org">Python Gentoo Team</mail>, with 11
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=python@gentoo.org">zamkniętych bugów</uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Nowe Bugi</title>
<body>
<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, którym przydzielono najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
to:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for New Packages</mail>, 36 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="gnome-office@gentoo.org">GNOME Office</mail>, 33 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=gnome-office@gentoo.org">nowe bugi</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="metalgod@gentoo.org">Luis Medinas</mail>, 24 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=metalgod@gentoo.org">nowe bugi</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for Orphaned Packages</mail>, 10 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="x11-drivers@gentoo.org">X11 External Driver Maintainers</mail>, 9 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=x11-drivers@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org">Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, 8 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="mobile@gentoo.org">Mobile Herd</mail>, 8 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=mobile@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
<li><mail link="sci@gentoo.org">Gentoo Science Related Packages</mail>, 7 
<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-10-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-11-05&amp;assigned_to=sci@gentoo.org">nowych bugów</uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- end of paste from bugzilla script -->

<!-- GWN feedback information -->
<chapter>
<title>Opinie czytelników</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Jeśli chcesz, aby ten magazyn był jeszcze lepszy, podziel się z
<mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">nami</mail> swoją opinią na jego temat.
Uwagi dotyczące tłumaczenia tygodnika można zgłaszać na adres
<mail link="rane@gentoo.org">rane@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- GWN subscription information -->
<chapter>
<title>Subskrypcja Tygodnika Gentoo</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Aby zaprenumerować Tygodnik Gentoo, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres
<mail>gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<p>
Aby zrezygnować z subskrypcji, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres <mail>
gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail> z konta, na które jest zarejestrowana.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Other Languages -->
<chapter>
<title>Inne języki</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Tygodnik Gentoo jest dostępny w następujących językach:
</p>

<ul>
<li>
<uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">angielskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">duńskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">francuskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">hiszpańskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">holenderskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japońskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ko/gwn/gwn.xml">koreańskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">niemieckim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Brazylia)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Portugalia)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">rosyjskim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">tureckim</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">włoskim</uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>

