<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20060116-newsletter.xml" lang="pl">
<title>Tygodnik Gentoo</title>
<subtitle>16 stycznia 2006</subtitle>
<author title="Redaktor naczelny">
<mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="uberlord@gentoo.org">Roy Marples</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="marienz@gentoo.org">Marien Zwart</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="jbozanowski@gmail.com">Jakub Bożanowski</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="karol.kania@gmail.com">Karol Kania</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="damian@lezajsk.info">Damian Kuras</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="moloh@gentoo.org">Michał Kurgan</mail>
</author>
<author title="Korektor">
<mail link="muchar@gentoo.org">Robert Muchacki</mail>
</author>
<author title="Korektor">
<mail link="herkii@gmail.com">Tomasz Muszyński</mail>
</author>
<abstract>Wydanie Tygodnika Gentoo z 16 stycznia 2005.</abstract>
<summary/>
<version>Wolumin 5, numer 2</version>
<date>2005-01-16</date>

<!-- Gentoo News -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo news</title>
<section>
<title>New USE defaults in the making</title>
<body>
<p>
For some packages portage has auto-use entries, which means that
unless you explicitly override a USE flag it will be enabled after
emerging a package and disabled after unmerging it. Example: after
"<c>emerge sqlite</c>" the <path>sqlite</path> flag will show up as 
enabled in "<c>emerge info</c>" and "<c>emerge -vp</c>" of something
that has <path>sqlite</path> in <path>iuse</path> unless you have
"<path>-sqlite</path>" or "<path>-*</path>" in USE in <path>make.conf</path>. 
If you unmerge <c>sqlite</c> the USE flag will show up as disabled 
again (unless you have <path>sqlite</path> in USE in <path>make.conf</path>
of course).
</p>
<p>
This has caused some annoyances as USE flags tend to "randomly" jump
when a new package triggers auto-use (either because you emerged or
unmerged it or because the <path>package.use</path> file in the tree was
edited). Many bugs have been filed, the general consensus is to phase
out auto-use.
</p>
<p>
The change will happen in one of the next Portage 2.1 releases - it is
in the tree and marked ~ARCH on almost all arches. "Stable" users will
stay unaffected for some time since Portage 2.0.x will not change its
behaviour, but upgrades can and will change USE flags. If you just
upgraded to a portage 2.1 release you will probably want to look at the
"<c>emerge -DuvpN world</c>" output and add flags that you want to keep
enabled to <path>make.conf</path> if they show up as "<path>-foo*</path>".
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Baselayout changes</title>
<body>
<p>
The Gentoo baselayout team is pleased to release <path>baselayout-1.12.0_pre14</path>
to the eagerly awaiting public. Here's a summary of the major changes since 1.11:
</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Network backgrounding support from wpa_supplicant, ifplugd and 
netplug with service dependency restart</b> -- Typically <c>ifplugd</c> is 
used to monitor ethernet cable being in/out and start/stop the network service 
accordingly, along with the services depending on that network service. The 
problem was that when <c>ifplugd</c> re-started the network service it didn't 
restart the services it stopped! Now <c>ifplugd</c> and <c>netplug</c> support 
have been merged into <path>baselayout</path>, we have more direct control and 
can remember which services were stopped by the network service so we can 
re-start them. <c>wpa_supplicant</c> can now do this too.
</li>
<li>
<b>Separate network configuration per interface</b> -- Each interface is 
now able to have its own <path>resolv.conf</path> and default route. We 
also prioritize wired over wireless and merge resolv.confs together. This 
works great for roaming laptop users.
</li>
<li><b>Interactive startup</b>  -- Do you have a service that causes serious 
issues when booting? You should not, but if you do then you can now choose 
to start, skip, continue or drop to shell for each service interactively. 
Using generic <path>stty</path> and shell calls we do this in a non-blocking 
way without the need for a daemon. 
</li>
<li>
<b>Parallel startup/shutdown improvements</b> -- Parallel startup and shutdown 
didn't really do what it claimed to in previous releases, but now it's very 
parallel and much faster than before. Which leads us onto ....
</li>
<li><b>Improved service dependency ordering (albeit slower)</b> -- Thanks to 
parallel startup, we found that our service ordering was totally wrong. So we 
had to re-write it entirely. So far it's in its fourth re-write using a 
topological sort written in bash and has been doing a very good job for around 
three months now so we think we've finally cracked it.
</li>
<li><b>Service daemon status checks</b> -- Services that launch daemons via 
start-stop-daemon now ensure that they really start instead of start - become 
daemon - die due to invalid config fooling <c>rc</c> into thinking they have 
started. Also, if you check a service status we check if the daemon is still 
running or not. If not then we stop the service and dependencies. We also 
really stop the service, which fixes an issue where you start <c>cups</c>, 
re-emerge <c>cups</c> and then it cannot stop or restart.
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Gentoo PPC meeting defines roadmap for 2006.0 and beyond</title>
<body>
<p>
The PPC developers spent three hours on Sunday night to discuss what lies 
ahead of them. The 2006.0 release for PowerPCs will include generic stages 1, 
2 and 3, specific stage3 tarballs for G3 and G4, both a minimal and a complete
install CD, plus GRP packages on a separate CD image. All 2006.0 profiles,
generic and optimized, will include NPTL support.
</p>
<p>
The PPC team will tackle some of the open bugs when another PPC bugday will focus 
the efforts of developers and users. If you'd like to participate in weeding out 
some of the undergrowth, tune into <path>#gentoo-ppc</path> on <path>irc.freenode.net</path> 
next Saturday, 21 January 14:00 UTC. Before starting a recruitment campaign for 
new develpers, the team is currently evaluating who among the 21 listed PPC devs 
is currently active or de-facto retired. Along with boosting the activity level 
within the team, they're also planning to enhance communication with other 
architectures and users by starting a mark-up of their blog posts and sending 
heads-up to the GWN team on a regular basis.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>AMD 64 project update</title>
<body>
<p>Major highlights from the Gentoo Linux for AMD64 activities have been included 
in a status report published by the Gentoo AMD64 project last week. As the hardware
has become more affordable, 2005 saw the user base grow a lot, and the number of
developers didn't stand back: The AMD64 team started with nine developers 
at the beginning of 2005, and currently counts 32 active developers, plus 16
"arch testers", i.e. power users putting the development under close scrutiny and
filing bug reports. The "arch testers" concept works so well that the idea has 
gained popularity with other architectures who are now considering setting up tester 
teams of their own. See <uri 
link="http://www.gentoo.org/proj/en/base/amd64/status/status_20060110.xml">the entire 
report</uri> for more accomplishments of the AMD64 team.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Future zone -->
<!-- User Stories -->
<!-- Gentoo Stories -->
<!-- Developer of the week -->

<!-- Heard in the community: gentoo-dev, gentoo-user, forums -->
<chapter>
<title>Społeczność Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Forum</title>
<body>
<p><b>Przygotowania do nowego wydania na architekturze SPARC</b></p>
<p>
Deweloperzy Gentoo SPARC przygotowują się do wydania 2006.0. <uri
link="gustavoz@gentoo.org">Gustavo Zacarias</uri> oznaczył nowy <c>gcc</c>
(3.4.5), <path>glibc</path>, a także jądro w wersji 2.6.11 jako stabilne. Zmiana
ta nie wypłynie na użytkowników starego profilu 2005.1, ale jako że wymaga ona
przeinstalowania całego systemu warto przeczytać ten wątek, gdyż znajdują się w
nim cenne wskazówki i porady co należy robić, gdy w trakcie aktualizacji
napotkamy problemy.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri link="https://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic-t-419845.html">New stable toolchain 
stuff on SPARC, read before using!</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo international -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo international</title>
<section>
<title>USA: Gentoo classes at MIT</title>
<body>
<p>
Gentoo developer <mail link="rajiv@gentoo.org">Rajiv Manglani</mail> will again
hold two evening seminars about Gentoo Linux for students of the Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology in Boston, MA. The first one (tomorrow, Tuesday) will give
an introduction to Gentoo, while the follow-up course on Thursday will provide a 
more detailled look at Portage and the creation of ebuilds. If you would like to 
attend one or both meetings, please contact <mail 
link="sipb-iap-gentoo@mit.edu">sipb-iap-gentoo@mit.edu</mail> today!
</p>
<ul>
<li>
<b>Introduction to Gentoo Linux:</b> Tuesday, 17 January 2006, 20:00-22:00, 
MIT Building 2, room 105
</li>
<li>
<b>Advanced Gentoo Linux:</b>Thursday, 19 January 2006, 20:00-22:00, same location</li>
</ul>
<note>Check <uri link="http://stuff.mit.edu/iap/gentoo/">the announcement</uri> at 
the MIT website for more details and instructions how to get to the venue on campus.</note>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>USA: Utah Gentoo user group</title>
<body>
<p>
<mail link="sdibb@myway.com">Steve Dibb</mail> is the founder of a group of 
Gentoo users in Utah. Located in West Jordan, he's recently set up <uri 
link="http://utah-gentoo.org">a website</uri> that uses "a vanilla install of 
Geeklog" to provide state-wide support and articles about Gentoo (first entry 
is a review of <mail link="dams@gento.org">Damien Krotkine's</mail> <c>flagedit</c> 
tool), and serves as a starting point for future activities like meetings and 
installfests. "Utah is actually a cool place for all the Linux support going 
around," says Steve, which orginally made him worry a bit: "I had sent out <uri
link="http://uphpu.org/pipermail/uphpu/2005-October/004078.html">an e-mail</uri> 
a few months earlier to see if there was any interest, and to my surprise there was quite 
a positive response to the idea, despite that fact that there are already
a lot of local Linux, Unix or other FOSS groups and mailing lists in the state." 
The one-month-old Gentoo Utah group now counts eleven members, all of whom use 
Gentoo in both production and private environments. On top of the website Steve
is hosting a mailing list where "we don't get flamed for using Gentoo like we 
would on the other local mailing lists" and which benefits from being small and
local: "The list gives us a chance to discuss Gentoo, without being flooded from 
a larger userbase."
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo in the press -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo w prasie</title>
<section>
<title>Allround PC (9 stycznia 2006, w języku niemieckim)</title>
<body>
<p>
Budowa systemu kina domowego bazująca na komputerze PC (ang. home theater PC
(HTPC)) wyposażonym w system Gentoo Linux jest jednym z doskonałych przykładów
zalet konfiguracji minimalnego systemu, jaki otrzymujemy po instalacji Gentoo.
Taka procedura była opisywana już wiele razy, ale w tym <uri
link="http://www.allround-pc.com/index.php?reviews/06009/bericht.htm">opisie</uri>
krok-po-kroku, znajdziemy także porady jaki sprzęt powinniśmy użyć, listę
modułów i ich konfigurację, informacje o zdalnej kontroli z użyciem pilota, a
także wiele innych. Należy zauważyć, że nie wszystkie opisywane w artykule
pakiety znajdują się w oficjalnym drzewie Portage, i znajdziemy w nim odnośniki
do <uri link="http://www.gentoo.de/main/de/downloads.xml">nakładki
gentoo.de</uri> zawierającej wszystkie brakujące ebuildy m.in. dodatkowe wtyczki
VDR, które są potrzebne by skonfigurować HTPC.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Distrowatch (9 January 2006)</title>
<body>
<p>
Ladislav Bodnar from Distrowatch picked up a piece of Gentoo documentation,
the new <uri link="/doc/en/liveusb.xml">Gentoo Linux LiveUSB Howto</uri> that 
"has now become part of the project's official documentation," and which <uri
link="http://distrowatch.com/weekly.php?issue=20060109#1">he finds</uri> 
"particularly useful for installing Gentoo Linux on a modern laptop with no 
CD-ROM drive." 
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Linuxdevices.com (11 January 2006)</title>
<body>
<p>
An article about a <uri link="http://www.linuxdevices.com/news/NS4842769131.html">Linux 
robot site</uri> that launched a user-controllable robot appeared on the pages of the
embedded online magazine Linuxdevices.com last week. 
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Tips and Tricks -->
<!-- Gentoo developer moves -->
<chapter>
<title>Zmiana statusu deweloperów Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Odeszli</title>
<body>
<p>
Następujący deweloperzy opuścili projekt Gentoo Linux w minionym tygodniu:
</p>
<ul>
<li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Przybyli</title>
<body>
<p>
Następujący deweloperzy przyłączyli się do projektu Gentoo Linux w minionym
tygodniu:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Martin Ehmsen (ehmsen) - TeX</li>
<li>Michal Kurgan (moloh) - koordynator polskiego tłumaczenia GWN</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Zmienili status</title>
<body>
<p>Następujący deweloperzy zmienili w minionym tygodniu pełnioną w projekcie Gentoo
 Linux funkcję:</p>
<ul>
<li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo security -->
<chapter>
<title>Bezpieczeństwo Gentoo</title>
<!-- paste from the script -->
<section>
<title>mod_auth_pgsql: Wiele usterek format string</title>
<body>
<p>
mod_auth_pgsql zawiera wiele usterek format string, których skutkiem może być
wykonanie niepożądanego kodu.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200601-05.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>xine-lib, FFmpeg: Przepełnienie bufora na stercie</title>
<body>
<p>
xine-lib i FFmpeg zawierają usterkę przepełnienia bufora, która może zostać
wykorzystania do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200601-06.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Blender: Przepełnienie bufora na stercie</title>
<body>
<p>
Blender jest podatny na usterkę przepełnienia bufora, która może zostać
wykorzystana przez napastnika do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200601-08.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Wine: Usterka SETABORTPROC w obsłudze plików WMF</title>
<body>
<p>
Wine zawiera usterkę w obsłudze plików Windows Metafiles (WMF), która może
zostać wykorzystana przez napastnika do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200601-09.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<!-- end of paste from the script -->
</chapter>
<!-- Bugzilla -->
<!-- paste from the script -->
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Statystyki</title>
<body>
<p>
Społeczność Gentoo używa Bugzilli (<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) do zgłaszania i śledzenia
błędów, ogłoszeń, sugestii oraz innych form kontaktu z deweloperami. Pomiędzy 8
stycznia 2006, a 15 stycznia 2006 aktywność w serwisie przedstawiała się
następująco:
</p>
<ul>
<li>zgłoszono 799 nowych bugów</li>
<li>zamknięto lub rozwiązano 447 bugów</li>
<li>37 uprzednio zamkniętych bugów zostało ponownie otwartych</li>
</ul>
<p>
Spośród 9083 obecnie otwartych bugów: 77 oznaczono jako 'blocker', 176 jako
'critical', a 489 jako 'major'.
</p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Zamknięte Bugi</title>
<body>
<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, które zamknęły najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
 to:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org">Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, 29
<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org">AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, 22 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org">zamknięte
bugi</uri></li>
<li><mail link="printing@gentoo.org">Printing Team</mail>, 17 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=printing@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="ppc@gentoo.org">PPC Porters</mail>, 15 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=ppc@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="games@gentoo.org">Gentoo Games</mail>, 14 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="perl@gentoo.org">Perl Devs @ Gentoo</mail>, 11 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=perl@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="dragonheart@gentoo.org">Daniel Black</mail>, 10 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=dragonheart@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="vapier@gentoo.org">SpanKY</mail>, 9 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=vapier@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Nowe Bugi</title>
<body>
<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, którym przydzielono najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
to:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for New
Packages</mail>, 49 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for Orphaned
Packages</mail>, 12 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="mozilla@gentoo.org">Mozilla Gentoo Team</mail>, 10 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=mozilla@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org">AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, 10 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="games@gentoo.org">Gentoo Games</mail>, 8 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="security@gentoo.org">Gentoo Security</mail>, 7 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="metalgod@gentoo.org">Luis Medinas</mail>, 7 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=metalgod@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org">Gentoo KDE team</mail>, 7 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-01-08&amp;chfieldto=2006-01-15&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- end of paste from bugzilla script -->
<!-- GWN feedback information -->
<chapter>
<title>Opinie czytelników</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Jeśli chcesz, aby Tygodnik Gentoo był jeszcze lepszy, podziel się z <mail
link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">nami</mail> swoją opinią na jego temat. Uwagi
dotyczące tłumaczenia można zgłaszać na adres <mail
link="moloh@gentoo.org">koordynatora</mail>.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- GWN subscription information -->
<chapter>
<title>Subskrypcja Tygodnika Gentoo</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Aby zaprenumerować Tygodnik Gentoo, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres
<mail>gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<p>
Aby zrezygnować z subskrypcji, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres <mail>
gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail> z konta, na które jest
zarejestrowana.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Other Languages -->
<chapter>
<title>Inne języki</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Tygodnik Gentoo jest dostępny w następujących językach:
</p>

<ul>
<li><uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">angielskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">duńskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">francuskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">hiszpańskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">holenderskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japońskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ko/gwn/gwn.xml">koreańskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">niemieckim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Brazylia)</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Portugalia)</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">rosyjskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">tureckim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">włoskim</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>

