<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20060619-newsletter.xml" lang="en">
  <title>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter</title>
  <subtitle>19 June 2006</subtitle>
  <author title="Editor">
    <mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="christel@gentoo.org">Christel Dahlskjaer</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="dertobi123@gentoo.org">Tobias Scherbaum</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="mark_alec@gentoo.org">Mark Kowarsky</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="jokey@gentoo.org">Markus Ullmann</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="beandog@gentoo.org">Steve Dibb</mail>
  </author>
  <author title="Author">
    <mail link="lucas.chiesa@gmail.com">Lucas Chiesa</mail>
  </author>	
  <abstract>This is the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter for the week of 19 June
    2006.</abstract>
  <summary/>
  <version>Volume 5, Issue 22</version>
  <date>2006-06-19</date>
  
  <!-- Gentoo News -->
  <chapter>
    <title>Gentoo news</title>
    <section>
      <title>Userrel wants YOU! - User Representatives Nominations</title>
      <body>
        <p>
          As one of the major distributions at the moment, Gentoo's
          organisation can be a fiendishly complicated thing to understand, and it can be
          difficult to know how you can help out. To this end, we have created the
          position of 'user representative', and would like to take this opportunity to
          explain something about the role.
        </p>

        <p>
          "Know thy users" is popular advice, and often we attempt to
          achieve this by consultation with one or more users. People will
          tend to err towards the idea of the statistical 'average user' -- one
          speaks for all. Although this approach is a simple and oftentimes
          effective way to find a representative user, the results are only valuable if
          the user base, their day-to-day tasks and work settings are
          homogeneous. If there are significant variations, this approach will fail to
          support some users, and can result in a product that does not meet
          their needs. It relies heavily upon having selected the most important
          user attributes for sampling and consultation, and can easily
          tempt us to think that knowing the characteristics of the average user,
          we need not consult with them. In this way it discourages us from
          challenging our own assumptions, and may deny us a source of valuable
          information that could prevent mistakes.
        </p>
        
        <p>
          The User Relations project focuses on bridging the gap
          between the developer and user communities, actively seeking out ways to
          improve communications between the two and encourage user
          involvement. It aims to ensure that high standards are met, and to work closely
          with other user focused projects to produce the best distribution
          possible for the user base. To this end, it is looking for user
          representatives to help in this quest.
        </p>
        
        <p>
          The project has decided that 5 user representatives should be
          enough to provide a sufficiently diverse range of opinions and
          interests while avoiding the issues associated with having too many.
          Nominations are now open; see <uri link="https://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic-t-470136.html">this
            forum thread</uri> for more information and to nominate
          any users you would like to see considered for the position.
        </p>
        
        <p><b>What does a User Representative do?</b></p>
        
        <p>Becoming a user representative may take some time, energy and
          commitment, but it can also be very rewarding. The role of
          user representative involves:</p>
        <ul>
          
          <li>Present the views, and represent the interests, of all
            elements of our diverse user base.</li>
          
          <li>Be a 'critical friend' to the User Relations project,
            offering alternative opinions and perspectives, and challenging
            the assumptions of all involved wherever appropriate.</li>
          
          <li>Engage positively with developers and Gentoo
            projects</li>
          
          <li>Interact with a wide range of groups and individuals to
            find out what our users think, and what they would like to see
            happening.</li>
          
          <li>Suggest ways in which other users could be engaged and
            involved in the project, in planning and delivering information and
            elsewhere.</li>
          
          <li>Channel information back to the users regarding
            proceedings of and decisions made in meetings.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p>
          If you were thinking of becoming a user representative, you
          will not be left alone. The user relations project will be there to
          support you, and you will be assigned a current developer as a point of
          contact with whom you can discuss any questions or concerns about your
          role or the group as a whole.
        </p>
        
        <p><b>Why become a user representative?</b></p>
        <ul>
          
          <li>You will have the opportunity to influence how
            information, news, and support are delivered to users, and to ensure that they
            are organised in the best way possible for all our users.</li>
          
          <li>You will gain experience as an advocate for the user
            community, and useful knowledge and skills that can be applied in many
            areas of life.</li>
          
          <li>It is a great way to give something back to the
            community, and to get involved as a user.</li>
          
          <li>You will have the chance to meet and get to know other
            users and developers.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p><b>What makes a good user representative?</b></p>
        
        <p>The ideal user representative would:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Be willing to network with a wide range of other
            users.</li>
          
          <li>Be seen as approachable by others, so that people will
            be open about their views. Be non-judgemental and show sensitivity
            towards what may be difficult issues.</li>
          
          <li>Work constructively with developers and staff. Not be
            scared or intimidated by developers, but to view them as people
            doing the best they can within constraints. Should it be necessary to
            challenge them, do so in a supportive manner wherever possible.</li>
          
          <li>Be able to negotiate, to make the case for a particular
            course of action, and willing to compromise where
            appropriate.</li>
          
          <li>Be able to step outside of his/her own experience, and
            be able to argue a viewpoint with which you may not fully
            agree.</li>
          
          <li>Present users' views with confidence, and not be afraid
            to raise issues about the role or the workings of the
            project.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p><b>Where can i learn more?</b></p>
        
        <p>
          We hope that most questions will have been answered above,
          but for any more information please do get in touch with the user
          relations team by one of the following methods:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>gentoo-userrel mailing list -- to subscribe, send a
            blank email to gentoo-userrel+subscribe@gentoo.org; the address to post
            is then gentoo-userrel@gentoo.org.</li>
          <li>By email to userrel@gentoo.org.</li>
          <li>In IRC: #gentoo-userrel on irc.freenode.net.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p><b>Other ways to get involved</b></p>
        <p>
          There are a number of areas in which interested users can
          contribute to Gentoo:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><b>Gentoo Linux Development team</b>: Prospective
            developers are encouraged to become active on bugzilla. The bug reports are
            monitored by development recruiters, so start squashing bugs and you
            will become noticed.</li>
          
          <li><b>Gentoo Bugdays</b>: On the first Saturday of each
            month both developers and users gather in #gentoo-bugs on irc.freenode.net
            where bugs are tested, discussed and resolved. Bugdays offer a great
            way for developers and users to work together and get to know
            each other. It also provides an opportunity for potential developers to
            be scouted. For further information the Bugday team can be
            contacted.</li>
          
          <li><b>Gentoo Linux Documentation team</b>: The team
            provides users with	clear and concise documentation. It is comprised of Technical
            Writers, Editors/Proofreaders, and Translators. For more
            information on joining take a look at the Gentoo Linux Documentation
            Policy.</li>
          
          <li><b>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter</b>: If you would like to
            offer your help to the GWN team as a contributor or translator then contact
            information can be found in the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter Overview.</li>
          
          <li><b>#gentoo IRC Channel</b>: Knowledgeable users are
            encouraged to come and help out in #gentoo on
            irc.freenode.net.</li>
          
          <li><b>#gentoo-dev-help IRC Channel</b>: Anyone wanting to
            know more about ebuild writing and/or Gentoo development is welcome to come and
            ask in #gentoo-dev-help on Freenode, where developers and other
            users are waiting to help. </li>
        </ul>
      </body>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>nss_ldap breakage and how to prevent it</title>
      <body>
        <p>With the upgrade to nss_ldap-249 and later many users found
          their	system in an almost unusable state: Upon boot it could take an extremely long time (up to an hour) to get to a login prompt. This is caused by a small change 
          in behaviour: What used to be a fixed timeout is now a
          configurable amount of attempts with increasing time between them. Information how
          to fix this problem can be found here:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><uri link="http://robbat2.livejournal.com/199841.html">Upgrading/using nss_ldap/nss_mysql/nss_nis/nss... and not breaking your system</uri></li>
        </ul>
      </body>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Project Sunrise - Gentoo User Overlay</title>
      <body>
        <p>
          Last week saw the announcement of an overlay for user-submitted ebuilds. This was intended to help users to find and use ebuilds that for now only exist in Gentoo Bugzilla and to ensure that these ebuilds adhere to minimal quality standards. Also it might offer a good environment for recruiting new ebuild developers from the user community.
        </p>
        <p>
          Giving commit access to this repository to trusted users has caused some very intense debates, centering mostly around policies and potential problems from malicious users. During the council meeting on June 16th it was decided that while the idea is quite good the execution was lacking.
        </p>
        <p>
          As a consequence the Sunrise overlay has been suspended from
          official Gentoo hardware, but it does continue on <uri link="http://gentoo-sunrise.org">gentoo-sunrise.org</uri> as an inofficial project. 
        </p>
        <p>
          Sunrise is looking for more users to add ebuilds from bugzilla to the overlay. You can find more information about Sunrise and its goals on <uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/proj/en/sunrise"> the project page</uri> and have a look at the <uri link="http://gentoo-sunrise.org/cgi-bin/trac.cgi/wiki/SunriseFaq">FAQ</uri> as well as the actual <uri link="http://gentoo-sunrise.org/cgi-bin/trac.cgi/browser"> overlay.</uri> Feel free to visit the IRC channel - #gentoo-sunrise on irc.freenode.net awaits you!
        </p>
        </body>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Hungarian GWN translators</title>
        <body>
          <p>
            Recently a hungarian GWN translation has been considered. Right now we are looking for some translators to help with the task - if you are interested please send a notice to gwn-feedback@gentoo.org. Many thanks in advance!
          </p>
        </body>
      </section>
    </chapter>
    
    <chapter>
      <title>Heard in the community</title>
      <section>
        <title>planet.gentoo.org</title>
        <body>
          
          <p>
            <b>Gentoo multimedia FAQ</b>
          </p>
          
          <p>
            After seeing lots of similiar questions on the Gentoo
            Forums and the #gentoo IRC channel Steve Dibb started collecting questions for
            a multimedia FAQ. If you like to see common questions being answered in his
            FAQ <mail link="beandog@gentoo.org">let him know</mail>.
          </p>
          
          <ul>
            <li>
              <uri link="http://wonkabar.org/blog/?p=96">Gentoo multimedia FAQ</uri>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </body>
        </section>
        
        <section>
          <title>gentoo-dev</title>
          <body>
            <p><b>Project Sunrise</b></p>
            <p>
              The User Overlay project has caused much discussion and has been
              suspended for now. The following threads spawned from this announcement:
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38898">[ANNOUNCE]
                  Project Sunrise - Gentoo User Overlay </uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39002">Project
                  Sunrice: arch team perspective </uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39013">What is
                  "official"? </uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39043">Sunrise
                  Project -- Open questions post requirement </uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39166">Project
                  Sunrise -- Proposal </uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39250">Project
                  Sunrise overlay suspended pending Council resolution</uri></li>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39301">A
                  heretical thought? Blessing project sunrise as an almost-fork.
                </uri></li>
            </ul>
            
            
            <p><b>Defining the Tree: a proto-GLEP.</b></p>
            <p>
              <mail link="spb@gentoo.org">Stephen Bennett</mail> starts a discussion
              that has its roots in the "alternative package manager" threads of the
              last weeks. One issue that was often mentioned is the lack of a formal
              specification of the ebuild format, environment and many other small
              details. So Stephen intends to write, together with the portage team and
              other interested developers, a full specification if there is enough
              interest and support within the developer community - and, almost
              obviously, this idea is almost universally accepted as a good thing.
              
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39259">Defining
                  the Tree: a proto-GLEP </uri></li>
            </ul>
            
            
            <p><b>GWN issues</b></p>
            <p>
              Under the slightly unintuitive title "July Council Meeting: Requested
              Agenda Item" <mail link="christel@gentoo.org">Christel Dahlskjaer</mail>
              starts a discussion about the state of the GWN. There were some issues
              with past GWNs, especially with the limited availability of <mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>. As a positive sideeffect
              Christel and some other devs have joined the GWN and will try to help
              where they can.
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39141">July Council Meeting: Requested Agenda Item </uri></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>[RFC] i18n project</b></p>
            <p>
              <mail link="flameeyes@gentoo.org">Diego 'Flameeyes' Petteno</mail> asks
              for some input on one of his excellent ideas: An internationalization
              (i18n) team that translates programs (for example the help messages)
              instead of documentation. This should help improve the accessibility for
              non-english persons.
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/39131">[RFC] i18n
                  project </uri></li>
            </ul>
            
            
          </body>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter>
        <title>Gentoo International</title>
        <section>
          <title>Germany: FrOSCon, Bonn/Rhein-Sieg</title>
          <body>
            
            <p>
              Gentoo Developer <mail link="dertobi123@gentoo.org">Tobias Scherbaum</mail>
              will give two talks at the first <uri link="http://www.froscon.org">Free and
                Open Source Software Conference</uri> taking place at the University of Applied
              Sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg next weekend. His first talk is an introduction to
              Gentoo where he talks about Gentoo's history, Gentoo's current state and further
              development. The second talk covers Gentoo's usage in business environments and
              demonstrates Gentoo's strengths, but also areas where Gentoo needs to evolve.
              For more details check the <uri link="http://programm.froscon.org">FrOSCon
                lectures website</uri>.
            </p>
            
          </body>
</section>
        <section>
          <title>Gentoo Summer Camp 2006</title>
          <body>
            <p>
              From 26th to 27th August 2006 there will be the Gentoo Summer Camp (GSC) 2006. It will take place at the campground "Grosses Meer" (which means "Big Sea"). This campground is next to the lake "Grosses Meer" which is the fourth largest lake of Lower Saxony, Germany.
            </p>
            <p>
              An english forum exists, international visitors are especially welcome.
            </p>
            <ul> <li><uri link="http://gsc2006.nachtnebelnelken.de/viewtopic.php?t=66">GSC2006 announcement</uri>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </body>
        </section>
            </chapter>
      <!-- Gentoo in the press -->
      <chapter>
        <title>Gentoo in the press</title>
        <section>
          <title>gentoo.de: Guide to Portage 2.1 (13 June 2006)</title>
          <body>
            
            <p>
              The German community website gentoo.de published an
              article on new features and changed behaviour in <uri link="http://www.gentoo.de/main/de/portage-2.1.xml">Portage 2.1</uri>. Author
              <mail link="tobias.scherbaum@gentoo-ev.org">Tobias Scherbaum</mail>
              includes an overview, but also gives practical examples
              on how these new features can be used to improve your
              Gentoo experience.
              The article is currently only available in German, an
              English translation can be done on short notice if some people indicate
              interest.
            </p>
            
          </body>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Rapid GUI Development with QtRuby</title>
              <body>
              <p>
                Gentoo Developer <mail link="caleb@gentoo.org">Caleb Tennis</mail> has recently published a book called "Rapid GUI Development with QtRuby". It is available as PDF on the <uri link="http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/ctrubyqt/index.html">Pragmatic Programmer Website</uri>. While it does assume some basic working knowledge of Ruby it is intended to be easy to read and informative even for people not yet familiar with Qt. 
              </p>
              <p>
                Although it is not Gentoo-specific all testing of programs for this book happened on Gentoo. The QtRuby bindings can be emerged with "emerge qtruby", the KDE extension Korundum can also be emerged with "emerge korundum", so Gentoo users will have it especially easy if they wish to play around with these programs.
              </p>
              <p>
                Caleb Tennis has been a Gentoo developer for 3 years now and is part of the Ruby, Qt and KDE herds.
              </p>
            </body>
          </section>
        </chapter>
        
            <!-- Tips and Tricks -->
            <chapter>
              <title>Tips and tricks</title>
              <section>
                <title>Exploring portage features</title>
                <body>
                  
                  <p>
                    The new release of Portage 2.1 brings many features and
                    improvements.
                    While most of them are documented in the example make.conf and the portage man page they may not be obvious to most users, so we will show how to use some of these features.
                  </p>
                  
                  <p>
                    All the features have to be set in
                    <c>/etc/make.conf</c>.
                  </p>
                  
                  <p>
                    Portage is now able to download some package's source
                    code while compiling another. This can considerably reduce installation time
                    when emerging many packages. There's no need to run <c>emerge
                      --fetchonly</c> while doing a normal emerge anymore. You just have to add the
                    following option:
                  </p>
                  
                  <pre caption="Setting parallel-fetch in /etc/make.conf">
FEATURES="parallel-fetch"
                  </pre>
                  
                  <p>This feature appears to be non-functional in some of the
                    Portage 2.1 releases, but is expected to be fixed soon.</p>
                  
                  <p>
                    Another new option to reduce installation time yet a bit
                    more is confcache.
                    With this new feature portage caches many of the
                    tests configuration scripts do, thus making execution
                    faster. This comes with the small risk of caching wrong values, so be warned       that this feature is known to have a few bugs.
                    Since this package is currently keyworded on most
                    architectures, the required steps to enable it are:
                  </p>
                  
<pre caption="Enabling confcache">
<comment>Add this in /etc/make.conf</comment>
FEATURES="confcache"
<comment>We need to unmask the package before emerging it</comment>
echo "=dev-utils/confcache-0.4.2-r1 ~arch" >>
/etc/portage/package.keywords
<comment>Installing confcache</comment>
emerge -av confcache
<comment>On further installations. you'll see stuff like:</comment>
checking for i686-pc-linux-gnu-gcc... (cached) i686-pc-linux-gnu-gcc
checking whether we are using the GNU C compiler...(cached) yes
checking whether i686-pc-linux-gnu-gcc accepts -g... (cached) yes
</pre>
                
                <p>
                  Another important new feature is the ability to log all
                  the messages
                  ebuilds print. Which messages to log and how to do it is
                  configurable.
                  For example, to save just the warnings and errors in a
                  separate file for each
                  package we emerge, you have to add:
                </p>
                
                <pre caption="Configuring logging features in /etc/make.conf">
<comment>This sets what to log</comment>
PORTAGE_ELOG_CLASSES="warn error log"
<comment>And this is how to do it</comment>
PORTAGE_ELOG_SYSTEM="save"
                </pre>
                
                <p>
                  There are many more options like sending log messages
                  via email.
                  Please check out make.conf.example for further
                  information.
                </p>
              </body>
              </section>
            </chapter>
            <!-- Gentoo developer moves -->
            <chapter>
              <title>Gentoo developer moves</title>
              <section>
                <title>Moves</title>
                <body>
                  <p>
                    The following developers recently left the Gentoo
                    project:
                  </p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><e>Chris White*</e></li>
                  </ul>
                </body>
              </section>
              <section>
                <title>Adds</title>
                <body>
                  <p>
                    The following developers recently joined the Gentoo
                    project:
                  </p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><e>Chris White (chriswhite) (random stuff)*</e></li>
                  </ul>
                </body>
              </section>
              <section>
                <title>Changes</title>
                <body>
                  <p>The following developers recently changed roles within
                    the
                    Gentoo project:</p>
                  <ul>
                    <li>Patrick Lauer - GWN operational lead</li>
                  </ul>
                  <p>
                  Note: Chris White resigned and then retracted his resignation. To show this change in status he is mentioned both as leaving and newly joining.</p>
                </body>
              </section>
            </chapter>
            <!-- Gentoo security -->
            <!-- Bugzilla -->
            <!-- paste from the script -->
            <!-- GWN feedback information -->
            <chapter>
              <title>GWN feedback</title>
              <section>
                <body>
                  <p>
                    Please send us your <mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">feedback</mail> and
                    help make the GWN better.
                  </p>
                </body>
              </section>
            </chapter>
            <!-- GWN subscription information -->
            <chapter>
              <title>GWN subscription information</title>
              <section>
                <body>
                  <p>To subscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a
                    blank e-mail to
                    <mail link="gentoo-gwn+subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
                  </p> 
                  <p> To unsubscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a
                    blank e-mail to
                    <mail link="gentoo-gwn+unsubscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail>
                    from the e-mail address you are subscribed under.</p>
                </body>
              </section>
            </chapter>
            
            <!-- Other Languages -->
            <chapter>
              <title>Other languages</title>
              <section>
                <body>
                  <p>The Gentoo Weekly Newsletter is also available in the
                    following
                    languages:</p>
                  <ul>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">Danish</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">Dutch</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">English</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">German</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">French</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/ko/gwn/gwn.xml">Korean</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">Japanese</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">Italian</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">Polish</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">Portuguese
                        (Brazil)</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">Portuguese
                        (Portugal)</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">Russian</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">Spanish</uri>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">Turkish</uri>
                    </li>
                  </ul>
                </body>
              </section>
            </chapter>
          </guide>
