<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20060911-newsletter.xml" lang="pl">
<title>Tygodnik Gentoo</title>
<subtitle>11 września 2006</subtitle>

<author title="Redaktor naczelny">
  <mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
  <mail link="mark_alec@gentoo.org">Mark Kowarsky</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
  <mail link="dragonheart@gentoo.org">Daniel Black</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
  <mail link="pva@gentoo.org">Peter Volkov</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
  <mail link="musikc@charter.net">Chrissy Fullam</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="wolf31o2@gentoo.org">Chris Gianelloni</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
  <mail link="jbozanowski@gmail.com">Kuba Bożanowski</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
  <mail link="shadoww@gentoo.org">Damian Kuras</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
  <mail link="moloh@gentoo.org">Michał Kurgan</mail>
</author>


<abstract>Wydanie Tygodnika Gentoo z 11 września 2006.</abstract>
<summary/>

<version>Wolumin 5, numer 37</version>
<date>2006-09-11</date>

<!-- Gentoo News -->

<chapter>
<title>Gentoo news</title>
<section>
<title>New Gentoo Council elected</title>
<body>

<p>
The <uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/proj/en/council/">Gentoo Council</uri> is
the elected governing body of Gentoo and decides on global issues and policies
that affect multiple projects in Gentoo. It also serves as an appeal court for
disciplinary decisions. The Council members are elected for a year and must hold
monthly public meetings.
</p>

<p>
The new council for the coming year has been elected. The polls were open for
a one-month voting period, to allow all developers a chance to vote on their
elected representatives. The winners of this year's council vote are as follows:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Diego Pettenò (Flameeyes)</li>
<li>Mike Doty (KingTaco)</li>
<li>Danny van Dyk (Kugelfang)</li>
<li>Bryan Østergaard (kloeri)</li>
<li>Robin H. Johnson (robbat2)</li>
<li>Mike Frysinger (vapier)</li>
<li>Chris Gianelloni (wolf31o2)</li>
</ul>

<p>
Of the new council, only Mike Frysinger is returning for another tour. The GWN
staff wishes to congratulate all of the new council members and wishes them a
productive year.
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Donation from Cloanto: Amiga Forever CD</title>
<body>

<p>
This week, Gentoo received a donation of the <uri
link="http://amigaforever.com">Amiga Forever CD</uri> from Cloanto. The <uri
link="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amiga">Amiga</uri> is the family of personal
computers developed initially by Amiga Corporation and later by Commodore
International. These computers had great success due to their graphics and
sound, which were far ahead of their time. Therefore, Amiga received its
nickname, the ultimate games machine. These computers are in the past, but
fortunately, the power of modern PC hardware has made it possible to emulate
Amiga software and games. Gentoo provides two Amiga emulators
<c>app-emulation/uae</c> and <c>app-emulation/e-uae</c>. However, to make full
use of these programs, one must have access to an image of the Amiga Kickstart
ROM. To properly maintain these packages, access to the Amiga Kickstart ROM is
required for Gentoo developers.
</p>

<p>
The Amiga Forever CD is the award-winning Amiga preservation, emulation, and
support package, made by Cloanto, Amiga developers since 1986. Cloanto has made
this CD available to all Gentoo developers to aid in the maintenance of the
Amiga emulation programs.
</p>

<p>
Gentoo would like to thank Cloanto for this generous donation.
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Monolithic X no longer supported</title>
<body>

<p>
Developer <mail link="dberkholz@gentoo.org">Donnie Berkholz</mail> wrote to the
<c>gentoo-dev</c> mailing list about the discontinuation of support for the
monolithic X ebuilds. This means there will be no more fixes added to the
monolithic packages, including no more security fixes. Package maintainers
will begin removing dependencies for the monolithic ebuilds from their
packages. Donnie hopes to move the monolithic X ebuilds into an overlay soon.
</p>

<p>
Users still using the old monolithic ebuilds should upgrade to modular X using
the <uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/proj/en/desktop/x/x11/modular-x-howto.xml">
Migrating to Modular X HOWTO</uri> instructions.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Developer of the Week -->
<chapter>
<title>Developer of the week</title>
<section>
<title>"Gentoo, it's what all the cool kids are doing." -Joshua Nichols</title>
<body>

<figure link="/images/gwn/20060911_nichoj.jpg"
        short="nichoj"
        caption="Joshua Nichols, aka nichoj"/>

<p>
Developer Joshua Nichols, aka nichoj, resides in Boston, MA - known for their
baked beans and tea parties... OK, one in particular. He graduated last spring
from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute with a dual degree in Computer Science
and Psychology. At 23, Josh shares an apartment with three friends and one
phantom roommate. They have no pets, but Josh considers himself a dog lover and
hopes to have a German Shepard when he has more time and a bigger place.
</p>

<p>
Josh works for Banta Corporation, a print and supply chain management company,
not that anyone knows what that means. His office develops web applications,
both internal and external. Josh works with a team developing modular web
applications, primarily with Java and J2EE (like Eclipse, Tomcat, Spring, JDO,
web services, etc).
</p>

<p>
Nichoj claims some fairly canon interests as far as geekery goes. He enjoys
reading, mostly sci-fi and fantasy, and some occassional technical reference,
for a bit of light reading. He also really enjoys watching Adult Swim, but
don't we all?  When Josh manages to get out of the house, it may be for some
rollerblading or hackey sack, but will inadvertently end up like many Boston
festivities... having a few drinks with friends at one of the many Boston
drinking establishments.
</p>

<p>
Josh started using Gentoo back in his freshmen year at college. He had been a
Linux user for years but found that hand configuring things quickly became hard
to maintain and discovered that using Gentoo helped him maintain his computer
the way he wanted. About a year ago, Josh decided that he wanted to be more
involved with open source software. He started attending the LUG's, actively
reporting bugs, and helping people on IRC. He was becoming rather proficient
with Java, and was quickly recruited by karltk. Josh's current role with Gentoo
is one that he rather enjoys, as the Java Project Lead.
</p>

<p>
Perhaps the Gentoo achievement Josh is most proud of is his contribution to the
new Java system, which was released a few months ago. While it was mostly
developed by the time Josh joined the team, they did quickly realize that all
of their 400+ Java packages would have to be updated. Josh is very proud to
have contributed to the planning and execution, as well as working through the
inevitable rough edges upon rolling it to the ~arch masses. Of noteworthy
mention, Josh received his first 'hate mail' while working on this project; he
must have been doing something right. ;-)
</p>

<p>
Josh's primary desktop is an AMD64 box, sporting an X2 4400+, 4GB of RAM, and a
7800GT connected to a 24" LCD. He also has two Dell x86 laptops, an Athlon XP
file server, and a G5 desktop for some PPC goodness. His first apps launched?
Compiz and CGWD of course, shortly followed by GAIM, Firefox, and Thunderbird.
</p>

<p>
Josh's parting words were that of wisdom: "It may be obvious, but you should
enjoy what you do. This can be both applied to work within open source projects
or with a job. If you're doing something you can't enjoy, or even worse, hate,
well, that's bad mmmkay. It'll make your hair grey prematurely, and you might
even poke your own eyes out in frustration. I don't know about you, but I like
having both eyes. But seriously, I feel fortunate to be able to thoroughly
enjoy both my work for Gentoo and my day job."
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Heard in the community -->
<chapter>
<title>Społeczność Gentoo</title>
<!-- forums -->
<section>
<title>Forum</title>
<body>

<p>
<b>Graficzny edytor do tworzenia ebuildów</b>
</p>

<p>
Na Forum Gentoo zaproponowano stworzenie graficznego edytora, swoistego IDE,
którego celem byłoby tworzenie i testowanie ebuildów. Zwolennicy pomysłu
argumentują, że takie narzędzie z pewnością ułatwi tworzenie nowych ebuildów
pytając użytkownika o wszelkie wymagane informacje. Przeciwnicy natomiast
wskazują na skomplikowaną budowę i strukturę ebuildów, która z pewnością bardzo
utrudni, o ile nie uniemożliwi stworzenie odpowiedniej aplikacji, a ograniczenie
dostępnych opcji nie jest chyba dobrym rozwiązaniem. Niezależnie od tego, czy
sama idea jest dobra czy też nie, nie jest to pierwsza próba stworzenie takiego
edytora. Jednym z istniejących przykładów jest, nie rozwijany już, pakiet Abeni,
stworzony przez dewelopera Gentoo o pseudonimie Pythonhead.
</p>

<ul>
  <li><uri>https://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic-t-496403.html</uri></li>
  <li><uri>http://abeni.sourceforge.net/</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- planet.gentoo.org -->
<!-- gentoo-user -->
<!-- gentoo-dev -->
<!-- Gentoo International-->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo International</title>
<section>
<title>Australia: Software Freedom Day, Canberra</title>
<body>

<p>
<uri link="http://www.softwarefreedomday.org/">Canberra Software Freedom
Day</uri>, on the 9th of September, was an event talking about software
freedom, encouraging people to give Linux a go and handing out Gentoo,
<uri link="http://www.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu</uri>, and <uri
link="http://www.theopencd.org/">TheOpenCD</uri>. After the event, 48 people
have a new Gentoo Linux 2006.1 x86 LiveCD, and 23 have a 2006.1 amd64 LiveCD. 
</p>

<figure link="/images/gwn/20060911_sfd.jpg"
        short="The team"
        caption="The Software Freedom Day team" />

<note>
Left to Right: Rainer Klein, Neill Cox, Daniel Black (dragonheart), Brian
Bishop, Pascal Klein, David Symons, and Evan Leybourn -- Missing: Steve Walsh,
Troy Newell
</note>

<p>
All participants had a lot of fun meeting interesting people watching the 
<uri link="http://orange.blender.org/">Elephants Dream</uri> production. People
were interested in alternatives to avoid spyware/viruses,  making their old PC
hardware useful again as backup/storage servers and making old laptops usable 
again.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo in the press -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo w prasie</title>
<section>
<title>LinuxPlanet (7 września)</title>
<body>

<p>
W tym tygodniu w serwisie LinuxPlanet można znaleźć artykuł dotyczący <uri
link="http://www.sectoo.org/">Sectoo</uri>. Jest to dystrybucja LiveCD bazująca
na Gentoo Linux w której położono szczególny nacisk na sprawy związane z
bezpieczeństwem. Jej celem jest pomoc we wszelkich zadaniach i testach jakie
wykonują administratorzy w swojej codziennej pracy. Zawiera szereg narzędzi
które mogą być niezwykle pomocne w czasie zabezpieczania i nadzorowania pracy
sieci.
</p>

<ul>
  <li><uri
  link="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/reviews/6307/1/">Sectoo--A Live
  Look at Gentoo</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Tips and Tricks -->
<!-- Gentoo developer moves -->
<chapter>
<title>Zmiana statusu deweloperów Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Odeszli</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy opuścili projekt Gentoo Linux w minionym tygodniu:
</p>

<ul>
  <li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Przybyli</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy przyłączyli się do projektu Gentoo Linux w minionym
tygodniu:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>Javier Villavicencio (The_Paya) Gentoo/FreeBSD</li>
  <li>Mike Kelly (pioto) creandus/GLEP27/vim</li>
  <li>Vlastimil Babka (Caster) Java</li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Zmienili status</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy zmienili w minionym tygodniu pełnioną w projekcie Gentoo
Linux funkcję:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>Krzysiek Pawlik (nelchael) dołączył do zespołu PPC/Java</li>
  <li>Jorge Manuel B. S. Vicetto (jmbsvicetto) dołączył do projektu UserRel</li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo security -->
<chapter>
<title>Bezpieczeństwo Gentoo</title>
<!-- paste from the script -->
<section>
<title>Streamripper: Wiele usterek przepełnienia bufora</title>
<body>

<p>
Streamripper zawiera wiele usterek przepełnienia bufora, które mogą zostać
wykorzystane do wykonanie niepożądanego kodu.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200609-01.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>GTetrinet: Zdalne wykonanie niepożądanego kodu</title>
<body>

<p>
GTetrinet zawiera usterki zdalnego przepełnienia bufora, które mogą zostać
wykorzystane do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200609-02.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>OpenTTD: Zdalna usterka Denial of Service</title>
<body>

<p>
Serwer OpenTTD jest podatny na zdalny atak Denial of Service.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200609-03.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>LibXfont: Wiele usterek przekroczenia zakresu liczby całkowitej</title>
<body>

<p>
Wykryto usterkę przepełnienia bufora w praserze fontów PCF, która potencjalnie
może zostać wykorzystana do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200609-04.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>OpenSSL, biblioteki x86 dla AMD64: Podrobienie podpisu RSA</title>
<body>

<p>
OpenSSL zawiera błąd walidacji podpisów PKCS #1 v1.5.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="http://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200609-05.xml">komunikacie
GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Bugzilla -->
<!-- paste from the script -->
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Podsumowanie</title>
<body>

<ul>
  <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect2">Statystyki</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect3">Zamknięte bugi</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect4">Nowe bugi</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Statystyki</title>
<body>

<p>
Społeczność Gentoo używa Bugzilli (<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) do zgłaszania i śledzenia
błędów, ogłoszeń, sugestii oraz innych form kontaktu z deweloperami. Pomiędzy 3
września 2006, a 10 września 2006 aktywność w serwisie przedstawiała się
następująco:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>zgłoszono 929 nowych bugów</li>
  <li>zamknięto lub rozwiązano 565 bugów</li>
  <li>38 uprzednio zamkniętych bugów zostało ponownie otwartych</li>
</ul>

<p>
Spośród 11040 obecnie otwartych bugów: 38 oznaczono jako 'blocker', 124 jako
'critical', a 530 jako 'major'.
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Zamknięte Bugi</title>
<body>

<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, które zamknęły najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
to:
</p>

<ul>
  <li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org">Gentoo's Team for Core System
  packages</mail>, 31 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org">Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, 26
  <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org">AMD64 Project</mail>, 25 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="games@gentoo.org">Gentoo Games</mail>, 20 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="security@gentoo.org">Gentoo Security</mail>, 18 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="mips@gentoo.org">mips team</mail>, 18 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=mips@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="java@gentoo.org">Java team</mail>, 18 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=java@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="x11@gentoo.org">Gentoo X-windows packagers</mail>, 13 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=x11@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
  bugów</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Nowe Bugi</title>
<body>

<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, którym przydzielono najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
to:
</p>

<ul>
  <li><mail link="maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for New
  Packages</mail>, 42 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">nowe
  bugi</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org">Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, 15 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org">AMD64 Project</mail>, 15 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for Orphaned
  Packages</mail>, 14 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org">Gentoo KDE team</mail>, 9 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="net-im@gentoo.org">Gentoo net-im Herd</mail>, 8 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=net-im@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="java@gentoo.org">Java team</mail>, 8 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=java@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
  <li><mail link="robbat2@gentoo.org">Robin Johnson</mail>, 6 <uri
  link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-09-03&amp;chfieldto=2006-09-10&amp;assigned_to=robbat2@gentoo.org">nowych
  bugów</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- GWN feedback information -->
<chapter>
<title>Opinie czytelników</title>
<section>
<body>

<p>
Jeśli chcesz, aby Tygodnik Gentoo był jeszcze lepszy, podziel się z <mail
link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">nami</mail> swoją opinią na jego temat. Uwagi
dotyczące tłumaczenia można zgłaszać na adres <mail
link="moloh@gentoo.org">koordynatora</mail>.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- GWN subscription information -->
<chapter>
<title>Subskrypcja Tygodnika Gentoo</title>
<section>
<body>

<p>
Aby zaprenumerować Tygodnik Gentoo, należy wysłać pustego emaila na adres <mail
link="gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>

<p>
Aby zrezygnować z subskrypcji, należy wysłać pustego emaila na adres <mail
link="gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org">
gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail> z konta, na które jest
zarejestrowana.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Other Languages -->
<chapter>
<title>Inne języki</title>
<section>
<body>

<p>
Tygodnik Gentoo jest dostępny w następujących językach:
</p>

<ul>
  <li><uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">angielskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/zh_cn/gwn/gwn.xml">chińskim (uproszczony)</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">duńskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">francuskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/el/gwn/gwn.xml">greckim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">hiszpańskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">holenderskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japońskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/ko/gwn/gwn.xml">koreańskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">niemieckim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Brazylia)</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Portugalia)</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">rosyjskim</uri></li>
  <li><uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">włoskim</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>

