<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20060522-newsletter.xml" lang="pl">
<title>Tygodnik Gentoo</title>
<subtitle>22 May 2006</subtitle>
<author title="Redaktor naczelny">
<mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="sebastian@gentoo.org">Sebastian Bergmann</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="amne@gentoo.org">Wernfried Haas</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="halcy0n@gentoo.org">Mark Loeser</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="deadhead@gechi.it">Andrea Perotti</mail>
</author>
<author title="Redaktor">
<mail link="dertobi123@gentoo.org">Tobias Scherbaum</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="jbozanowski@gmail.com">Jakub Bożanowski</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="shadoww@gentoo.org">Damian Kuras</mail>
</author>
<author title="Tłumacz">
<mail link="moloh@gentoo.org">Michał Kurgan</mail>
</author>
<abstract>Wydanie Tygodnika Gentoo z 22 May 2006.</abstract>
<summary/>
<version>Wolumin 5, numer 19</version>
<date>2006-05-22</date>

<!-- Gentoo News -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo news</title>
<section>
<title>GCC 4.1 on its way into Portage</title>
<body>
<p>
The long awaited moment of GCC 4.1 being unmasked has almost arrived.  The
toolchain team will be unmasking gcc-4.1.1 this week after it is released.
The upgrade should be incredibly easy and require no additional work to
install and use.  The number of applications that do not compile with gcc-4.1
is extremely small now, and most users should not experience any problems
with <path>~arch</path> packages not compiling.  To upgrade to the new version (assuming
you are using gcc-3.4), all that is required is to upgrade GCC and then select
the new profile using gcc-config.  If you are upgrading from an earlier version
of GCC, please refer to our <uri link="/doc/en/gcc-upgrading.xml">GCC Upgrading 
Guide</uri> for more detailed instructions.
</p>
<p>
If you run into any applications that do not compile, and they do not have a
bug currently open, please file a "GCC Porting" bug and assign it to
<mail link="gcc-porting@gentoo.org">gcc-porting@gentoo.org</mail> so that 
the GCC Porting team can look into it.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Gentoo Summer of Code</title>
<body>
<p>
There were over 6400 applications from students, almost 90 mentoring
organizations - in almost every respect the Summer of Code program from
Google has grown a lot since last year. This year Gentoo will be one of 
the mentoring organizations, with the UserRel project acting as organizer. 
While the final numbers will be released on Monday the 22nd
we can already say that Gentoo got 130 applications. Out of these around
13 will be sponsored by Google. We are very happy to see such a great
interest in Gentoo and hope that all sponsored projects will be
successful! 
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Old-style PHP packages removed from Portage</title>
<body>
<p>
After being <path>package.mask</path>ed for quite some time, the old-style PHP
packages (<path>dev-php/php, dev-php/php-cgi, dev-php/mod_php</path>, and friends)
have been removed from the Portage tree. The new-style PHP packages
(<path>dev-lang/php, dev-php4/*, dev-php5/*</path>, and friends) are now stable on
most architectures.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Future zone -->
<!-- User Stories -->
<!-- Gentoo Stories -->
<!-- Developer of the week -->

<!-- Heard in the community: gentoo-dev, gentoo-user, forums -->
<chapter>
<title>Heard in the community</title>
<section>
<title>gentoo-dev</title>
<body>
<p><b>et_EE locale and language of error messages</b></p>
<p>
The Gentoo bugwranglers often have to wrangle bugs that have error
messages in other languages. This makes it difficult to understand and
to find duplicates. A workaround for this issue would be to set the
default language used by portage to "C", which is (through historic
precedents) English and the default when nothing else is set.
A different class of bugs comes from the estonian locale, et_EE: As
their alphabet ordering is different some "silly" buildsystems stumble
as [a-z] no longer matches all letters. While these bugs can be really
annoying they should be fixed. Setting the locale to another language
would prevent these bugs, but it is recommended to fix it so that future
problems are avoided.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38378">et_EE
locale and language of error messages </uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>New eclasses</b></p>
<p>
As there are many different Revision Control Systems and it is often
useful to have ebuild support to check out files directly from a
repository this week gives us a few eclasses that help with managing
darcs, git and mercurial. Those three are relatively new RCS that are
already used by many projects instead of CVS or subversion.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38364">New
eclasses </uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>Signing everything, for fun and for profit</b></p>
<p>
The first recorded discussions about signing all Gentoo-provided files
to avoid tampering go back to 2003. Since then there have been a few
tries to get a Gentoo-wide system to cryptographically sign all files,
but there was never a consensus, and in the end it never got fully
implemented. <mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
revives the discussion in the hope of getting it finally done.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38363">Signing
everything, for fun and for profit </uri></li>
</ul>

<p><b>RFC - Gentoo Knowledge Base</b></p>
<p>
A new Gentoo project gets kickstarted by <mail
link="swift@gentoo.org">Sven Vermeulen</mail>. The goal is to create a
knowledge base that "[...] provides answers to specific questions and problems
that users (or developers) might encounter. It is easily searchable and
maintained by developers who are knowledgeable in the topic. The
knowledge base entries ("topics" as I like to call them) are not
documentation guides, but very specific to a particular environment and
question."
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38030">RFC -
Gentoo Knowledge Base </uri></li>
</ul>

<p><b>Paludis profiles yay or nay?</b></p>
<p>
What started as a simple question by <mail link="spb@gentoo.org">Stephen
Bennett</mail> whether there were any objections to adding profiles for the
Paludis package manager into the mainline Gentoo tree became one of the
fastest and most heated email exchanges to happen on the <path>gentoo-dev</path>
mailinglist. With around 300 messages in the main thread and three
forked subthreads this is an impressive debate:
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38016">Paludis
and Profiles </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38231">Alternative
Gentoo package managers discussion request (for the council) </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38342">RFC:
etiquette enforcement </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/38351">259
paludis-profile messages. ENOUGH! </uri></li>

</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Planet Gentoo</title>
<body>
<p><b>Baselayout 1.12 going stable?</b></p>
<p>
Asked by many users Roy Marples now announced that there is only one 
unionfs bug left before he starts building baselayout's 1.12.0 tarball. 
If there don't occur any show-stopping bugs it will take another month 
before baselayout-1.12.0 can be marked stable by our ARCH-teams.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri link="http://roy.marples.name/node/261">
Baselayout 1.12 going stable?</uri></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Apache 2.0.58 now available</b></p>
<p>
Later than expected Apache 2.0.58 finally made it into the tree, including 
some changes how Apache works within Gentoo. Most notable is the deprecation 
of net-www/gentoo-webroot-default as discussed in Bug #90748. As of 2.0.58 
the /var/www/localhost directory will be left untouched if it exists. If 
it doesn’t exist, it will be created and populated.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://www.alteredeclipse.org/blog/projects/gentoo/apache/changes-2.0.58">
Apache 2.0.58 now available</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Gentoo international -->
<chapter>
<title>Międzynarodowe Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Austria: Gentoo na konferencji Grazer Linuxtage</title>
<body>
<p>
Jak pisaliśmy już w poprzednim numerze Tygodnika, Gentoo zaznaczyło swoją
obecność na imprezie Linuxtag w Graz. Markus Lang, <mail
link="roger55@gentoo.org">Roger Miliker</mail>, Gregor Perner i <mail
link="amne@gentoo.org">Wernfried Haas</mail> byli obecni przy stoisku
Gentoo, rozdając płyty LiveCD, sprzedając nalepki na obudowy komputerów,
rozmawiając z użytkownikami o Portage i rozdając naklejki. Jak zwykle
koledzy z grml (których stoisko sąsiadowało ze stoiskiem Gentoo) pytali, czy
nadal kompilujemy wszystko ze źródeł. W odpowiedzi dostali pokaz
instalatora. Oczywiście to tylko przyjacielskie zaczepki, ekipy Funkfeuer,
Gentoo, grml i Debiana dobrze się razem bawiły. Wernfried Haas prowadził
warsztaty wprowadzające do IRC-a, skupiając się na popularnym kliencie tej
usługi, <c>irssi</c> oraz omawiając sieć Freenode. Zarówno odwiedzający, jak
i wystawiający dobrze się bawili dzięki sprawnej organizacji. Do zobaczenia
w roku 2007!
</p>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20060522_glt.jpg"
short="GLT"
caption="Amne poprawia kolejność słów" />
<note>Więcej zdjęć z imprezy można znaleźć pod adresem
http://dufo.tugraz.at/glt06/</note>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Włochy: Gentoo na konferencji Linux World Summit w Mediolanie</title>
<body>
<p>
Koledzy z GeCHI (Gentoo CHannel Italia www.gechi.it) spędzili na konferencji
Linux World Summit w Mediolanie dwa dni pełne wrażeń. W porównaniu z
poprzednimi latami zarezerwowano mniej powierzchni wystawowej w hotelu
Marriot i to najprawdopodobniej z tego powodu nie można było znaleźć zbyt
wielu stoisk należących do firm. Wystawy stowarzyszeń były za to większe,
bardziej kolorowe i zabawne. Zgodnie z przewidywaniami z zeszłego numeru
Tygodnika, GeCHI zademonstrowało komputer Sun Fire V120 i klaster OpenMosix,
na który składały się cztery płyty główne Via Epia. Oba komputery pracowały
pod kontrolą systemu Gentoo Linux. Tylko pierwszy węzeł klastra był
podłączony do dwóch dysków SATA, pozostałe trzy pracowały w konfiguracji
bezdyskowej i uruchamiały się przez sieć. Z powodu nietypowej obudowy
klaster był w centrum zainteresowania publiczności w trakcie obu dni trwania
wystawy. Członkowie GeCHI przygotowali także broszurki Gentoo, które
rozdawali przy stoisku, oraz sprzedawali pasujące do kompletu pingwiny i
krowy (o imieniu Larry).
</p>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20060522_gechi.jpg"
short="Gechi"
caption="Jeden Larry, cztery Tuksy: GeCHI przy pracy" />
<note>Od lewej do prawej, z tyłu: deadhead, blackman, ElDios, z przodu: mouser, 
riquitoi. Więcej zdjęć z imprezy możemy znaleźć na <uri 
link="http://dev.gechi.it/gallery/v/Eventi/lws06">stronie GeCHI</uri></note>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo in the press -->
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo in the press</title>
<section>
<title>Dot KDE (16 May 2006)</title>
<body>
<p>
In a series of interviews with businesses that benefit from KDE -- 
or vice-versa -- the KDE Dot News magazine spoke with Gentoo developer 
<uri link="http://dot.kde.org/1147698188/">Caleb Tennis</uri> in his 
professional quality as system designer at AEI, a company in Columbus,
Indiana, specializing in diesel engine durability assessment, exhaust
research, performance development and numerous other services. Caleb
sees reliability as a key element in AEI's decision to run Linux and 
KDE, as everything else "may be liveable on your girlfriend's computer, 
but for one that's monitoring a $1,000,000 development engine, it becomes 
pretty important to not have problems because 'Windows crashed'."
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Newsforge (19 May 2006)</title>
<body>
<p>
Gentoo trustee and infrastructure lead <mail link="klieber@gentoo.org">Kurt 
Lieber</mail> gets his say in an article about Gentoo sponsor OSUOSL titled
<uri link="http://mobile.newsforge.com/mobility/06/05/05/2018250.shtml">"Oregon 
lab plays Web host to the stars of open source."</uri> Setting the backdrop
for the following interview with OSUOSL's Scott Kveton, Kurt points out how
fabulous the open-source lab's services to Gentoo have been: "in fact, it's 
better than what I would expect from commercial vendors in a lot of respects."
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- Tips and Tricks -->
<chapter>
<title>Sztuczki i kruczki</title>
<section>
<title>Zarządzanie nakładkami za pomocą narzędzia layman</title>
<body>
<note>
To pierwszy dział Sztuczki i kruczki od dłuższego czasu. Prosimy o
nadsyłanie własnych propozycji porad, którymi chcielibyśmy podzielić się ze
społecznością Gentoo, na adres <mail
link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">gwn-feedback@gentoo.org</mail>.
</note>

<p>
<c>layman</c> to niewielka, lecz przydatna aplikacja napisana przez
dewelopera Gentoo, <mail link="wrobel@genoo.org">Gunnara Wrobela</mail>.
Umożliwia ona używanie i synchronizowanie wielu nakładek Portage na lokalnym
komputerze przy minimum wysiłku.
</p>

<p>
W chwili obecnej <c>layman</c> nie posiada jeszcze stabilnej wersji, dlatego
przed instalacją musimy dodać go do pliku <path>package.keywords</path>.
</p>

<pre caption="Instalowanie laymana">
# echo "app-portage/layman" >> /etc/portage/package.keywords
# emerge layman
</pre>

<p>
Aby dodać do naszej zmiennej <c>PORTDIR_OVERLAY</c> zarządzane przez
narzędzie <c>layman</c> nakładki, musimy wczytać plik, w którym są one
zdefiniowane. Zwróćmy uwagę, że wciąż mamy możliwość ręcznego dodania innych
nakładek do zmiennej <c>PORTDIR_OVERLAY</c> w pliku
<path>/etc/make.conf</path>.
</p>

<pre caption="Wczytywanie nakładek laymana">
# echo "source /usr/portage/local/layman/make.conf" >> /etc/make.conf
</pre>

<p>
Konfigurowanie programu <c>layman</c> to bułka z masłem. Najpierw należy
pobrać listę dostępnych nakładek, a następnie dodać te spośród nich, których
chcemy użyć.
</p>

<pre caption="Konfiguracja laymana">
<comment>Pobranie listy dostępnych nakładek</comment>
# layman -f

<comment>Dodanie nakładki 'gentoo-de'</comment>
# layman -a gentoo-de
</pre>

<p>
Wydając polecenie <c>layman -l</c> uzyskamy listę dostępnych nakładek, zaś
dodając parametr <c>-a</c> możemy dodać kolejne nakładki.
</p>

<p>
Uruchomienie programu z parametrem <c>-s</c> pozwala natomiast
zsynchronizować lokalne kopie nakładek. Możemy wybrać między
zsynchronizowaniem konkretnej nakładki lub wszystkich spośród do tej pory
dodanych.
</p>

<pre caption="Synchronizacja nakładek">
<comment>Synchronizowanie nakładki 'gentoo-de'</comment>
# layman -s gentoo-de

<comment>Synchronizacja wszystkich nakładek</comment>
# layman -s ALL
</pre>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo developer moves -->
<chapter>
<title>Zmiana statusu deweloperów Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Odeszli</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy opuścili projekt Gentoo Linux w minionym tygodniu:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Rob Holland</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Przybyli</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy przyłączyli się do projektu Gentoo Linux w minionym
tygodniu:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Steve Dibbs (beandog) - Planet</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Zmienili status</title>
<body>

<p>
Następujący deweloperzy zmienili w minionym tygodniu pełnioną w projekcie Gentoo
Linux funkcję:
</p>

<ul>
<li><e>Nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Gentoo security -->
<chapter>
<title>Bezpieczeństwo Gentoo</title>
<!-- paste from the script -->
<section>
<title>libextractor: Przepełnienie bufora na stercie</title>
<body>

<p>
libextractor zawiera dwie usterki przepełnienia bufora na stercie, które mogą
zostać wykorzystane do wykonania niepożądanego kodu.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200605-14.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Quagga Routing Suite: Wiele usterek</title>
<body>

<p>
Demon RIP w pakiecie Quagga umożliwia wstrzyknięcie tras rutingu oraz ujawnienie
informacji o rutingu. Demon BGP jest podatny na atak Denial of Service.
</p>

<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri
link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200605-15.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>

</body>
</section>
<!-- end of paste from the script -->
</chapter>

<!-- Bugzilla -->
<!-- paste from the script -->
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Statystyki</title>
<body>

<p>
Społeczność Gentoo używa Bugzilli (<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) do zgłaszania i śledzenia
błędów, ogłoszeń, sugestii oraz innych form kontaktu z deweloperami. Pomiędzy
14 maja 2006, a 21 maja 2006 aktywność w serwisie przedstawiała się następująco:
</p>

<ul>
<li>zgłoszono 653 nowe bugi</li>
<li>zamknięto lub rozwiązano 323 bugi</li>
<li>24 uprzednio zamknięte bugi zostały ponownie otwarte</li>
</ul>

<p>
Spośród 10139 obecnie otwartych bugów: 56 oznaczono jako 'blocker', 149 jako
'critical', a 524 jako 'major'.
</p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Zamknięte Bugi</title>
<body>
<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, które zamknęły najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
 to:
</p>

<ul>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org">Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, 21
<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="emacs@gentoo.org">GNU Emacs Herd</mail>, 16 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=emacs@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="security@gentoo.org">Gentoo Security</mail>, 15 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="games@gentoo.org">Gentoo Games</mail>, 14 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="robbat2@gentoo.org">Robin Johnson</mail>, 11 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=robbat2@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="dev-portage@gentoo.org">Portage team</mail>, 11 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=dev-portage@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="apache-bugs@gentoo.org">Apache Herd - Bugzilla Reports</mail>,
10 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=apache-bugs@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="ppc64@gentoo.org">ppc64 architecture team</mail>, 9 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=ppc64@gentoo.org">zamkniętych
bugów</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Nowe Bugi</title>
<body>

<p>
Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, którym przydzielono najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu,
to:
</p>

<ul>
<li><mail link="maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for New
Packages</mail>, 22 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-wanted@gentoo.org">nowe
bugi</uri></li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org">AMD64 Project</mail>, 17 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org">Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, 11
<uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="squinky86@gentoo.org">Jon Hood</mail>, 9 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=squinky86@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org">Gentoo's Team for Core System
packages</mail>, 9 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">Default Assignee for Orphaned
Packages</mail>, 8 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=maintainer-needed@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="flameeyes@gentoo.org">Diego Pettenò</mail>, 8 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=flameeyes@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org">Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, 7 <uri
link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2006-05-14&amp;chfieldto=2006-05-21&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org">nowych
bugów</uri></li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- end of paste from bugzilla script -->

<!-- GWN feedback information -->
<chapter>
<title>Opinie czytelników</title>
<section>
<body>

<p>
Jeśli chcesz, aby Tygodnik Gentoo był jeszcze lepszy, podziel się z <mail
link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">nami</mail> swoją opinią na jego temat. Uwagi
dotyczące tłumaczenia można zgłaszać na adres <mail
link="moloh@gentoo.org">koordynatora</mail>.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<!-- GWN subscription information -->
<chapter>
<title>Subskrypcja Tygodnika Gentoo</title>
<section>
<body>

<p>
Aby zaprenumerować Tygodnik Gentoo, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres <mail
link="gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-pl+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>

<p>
Aby zrezygnować z subskrypcji, należy wysłać pustego e-maila na adres <mail
link="gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org">
gentoo-gwn-pl+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail> z konta, na które jest
zarejestrowana.
</p>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<!-- Other Languages -->
<chapter>
<title>Inne języki</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Tygodnik Gentoo jest dostępny w następujących językach:
</p>

<ul>
<li><uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">angielskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">duńskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">francuskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">hiszpańskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">holenderskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japońskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ko/gwn/gwn.xml">koreańskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">niemieckim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Brazylia)</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Portugalia)</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">rosyjskim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">tureckim</uri></li>
<li><uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">włoskim</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>

